# SHANTEL HOGAN

Glenn Heights, Texas 75154 · (817) 353-1981 shantelhogan@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/shantel-hogan-764ab813a/

Analytical, organized and detail-oriented accountant with GAAP expertise and experience in the full spectrum of public accounting. A Collaborative team player who specializes in Oil and Gas Accounting, Banking, and Customer Service. A self-starter with ownership mentality and a track record of delivering the highest quality strategic solutions to resolve challenges, propel business growth. A strong team plater and fast learner with a commitment to perform to the highest standards with accuracy and timeliness as priorities.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**05/2021 TO PRESENT** 

### **CONTRACT SENIOR REVENUE ACCOUNTANT**

AETHON ENERGY, DALLAS, TEXAS

 Coordinating with Production Accounting and understanding production allocations, ensuring revenue settlements are booked in alignment of that data. Coordinating with Title and Lease Administration on Division of Interest maintenance and ownership transfers. Managing revenue related cash receipts and reconciliation to purchasing statements for product sales. Verifying revenue contract pricing. Analyzing sales volume determinations and meter volume data. Recording revenue and revenue related taxes and deducts for all products for both operated and non-operated properties. Generating revenue sales accruals. Compiling and creating gas balancing statements. Creating shipper statements for midstream clients. Processing Prior Period Adjustments (PPA's). Reporting and payment of state and federal royalty and tax obligations. Coordinating with Production Reporting to reconcile production and revenue reporting to state and federal regulatory agencies. Conducting revenue reconciliations and variance analysis for purchaser receivable, royalty, suspense, taxes payable accounts, etc. Participating in period closing activities, including processing of Prior Period Adjustments (PPA's). Assisting with owner relations inquiries. Following internal procedures and internal control policies. Assisting in internal and external audits. Assisting in other oil and gas accounting activities and special projects as needed, such as annual 1099 report generation and escheatment activities.

#### 2009 TO 05/2021

## **SENIOR REVENUE ACCOUNTANT**

### DIAMOND S ENERGY, FORT WORTH, TEXAS

Working in an oil and gas firm to provide professional accounting services for individuals
and business clients. Oversee monthly revenue processing and responsible for analyzing
and recording revenue accruals and reconciliations. Ensure payments of severance taxes
and assist with financial audit request. Process major month-end and mid-month
revenue check runs. Perform detailed analysis of the revenue checks generated each
month at both the owner level and the property level. Create and distribute various

monthly reports to external parties (e.g. JV Partners, certain royalty owners) Assist with special projects and other duties as assigned. Coordinate with other departments to obtain necessary data to conduct monthly duties. Process Revenue PPA's as needed. Create monthly and quarterly Journal Entries and prepare 1099s.

#### Success:

Manage \$3 million in monthly sales, ensuring accurate revenue recognition. Advanced to a position of increased responsibility due to superior performance and knowledge of position. Implemented new reporting and filing system for entire company.

#### 2007 - 2009

# **AP/REVENUE ACCOUNTANT I**

# PETROLEUM FINANCIAL, FORT WORTH, TEXAS

Code all invoices and accounts accurately ensuring funds were used in accordance with
company directives. Processed and reconciled reports including expense reports, prepaid
expenses, assets, and postage. Responsible for preforming various cash flow
reconciliations, disbursement, and forecasting. Coordinate month end closing procedures
to ensure corporate deadlines are met. Reviewed potential sales contracts and advised
on the resulting accounting treatment to ensure compliance with Generally Accepted
Accounting Principles. Record, review, and distribution of monthly gross revenue from
operated and non-operated properties.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **MAY 2020**

## BBA IN ACCOUNTING, NORTHWOOD UNIVERSITY

- Distinguished member of university's Accounting Society
- Relevant Coursework: Advanced Financial Accounting and Reporting, Accounting Systems,
   Financial Statement & Analysis, Auditing
- GPA: 3.2/4.0

#### **DECEMBER 2021**

# MLS IN OIL, GAS AND ENERGY LAW, UNIVERSITY OF OKLAHOMA

 Relevant Coursework: Negotiations & Ethics, Midstream Oil and Gas Law, Oil and Gas Regulatory Practice, Oil and Gas Contracts, Legal Drafting, Mineral Title Examination, Oil and Gas Law, Contracts- Energy Industry, Legal Research- Energy Industry, Project Economics and Finance, and Real Estate Transactions,

GPA: 3.6/4.0

# **SKILLS**

- E&P Oil and Gas accounting
- Revenue Accounting
- Royalty and Working interest requests
- JIB Accounting
- SOX Compliance
- Self-motivation
- Cashflow planning and management
- Adaptability
- Accounts Payable
- Accounts Receivable
- Financial Statements
- Microsoft Office advanced in Excel and Spreadsheets
- Business Administration
- Detail oriented
- Division Order Analyzing
- Time management and organization
- PPA processing
- Dedicated to managing multiple coherent deadlines

- Federal Railroad Commission & MMS Reporting
- Operating and Non-operating Wells
- Severance tax (TX, OK, LA, WY)
- State Withholdings
- Bookkeeping
- Cost Accounting
- Account Management
- General Ledger Reconciliations and Research
- Balance sheet
- Teamwork
- Customer service
- Exceptional oral and written communication
- Proficient in Ogsys and Enertia Software
- Aptitude for planning and executing multiple projects simultaneously

# **ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS**

- Reading
- Traveling
- Sewing

- Volunteer Work and Community involvement
- Cycling
- Music

References available upon request